<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on > Hi, I'm Jonathan 👋</title><link>https://ruffles.pw/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on > Hi, I'm Jonathan 👋</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ruffles.pw/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Benchmarking .NET CSV Parsers</title><link>https://ruffles.pw/posts/benchmarking-csv-parsers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruffles.pw/posts/benchmarking-csv-parsers/</guid><description>Introduction As part of my new job, I am around csv files quite a lot. One of the tasks internally was to design and create a package which read common csv files for the company, as a NuGet package, so it could be used across internal company tools.
Now, instead of writing an entire CSV parser, I decided to use an existing package, with a small intermediary layer which implemented business-specific details, such as models, and simpler interface.</description></item><item><title>A Decay Photodump</title><link>https://ruffles.pw/posts/decay-photos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruffles.pw/posts/decay-photos/</guid><description>These screenshots are arranged in no specific order or preference</description></item><item><title>Hugo: Making a portfolio site</title><link>https://ruffles.pw/posts/hugo-portfolio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruffles.pw/posts/hugo-portfolio/</guid><description>Why Hugo? If you choose to build your portfolio site using only HTML and CSS, you may run into the issue of repetitive code.
Example: Let&amp;rsquo;s say you have a blog post called my-blog-post.html and you want to create another post.
What do you do? You could duplicate the file and rewrite the content, but what if you change the layout of the post? You have to make the change in every file!</description></item><item><title>React vs Vue: First Look</title><link>https://ruffles.pw/posts/react-vs-vue-firstlook/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruffles.pw/posts/react-vs-vue-firstlook/</guid><description>Introduction Vue.js and React.js are two popular JavaScript libraries for building user interfaces (UI) and single-page applications (SPAs). Both libraries are widely used in the web development community and have a strong following among developers.
Vue.js, which was created by Evan You in 2014, is a progressive framework that is designed to be incrementally adoptable, meaning that it can be easily integrated into a project in small pieces rather than all at once.</description></item><item><title>My experience learning Kubernetes</title><link>https://ruffles.pw/posts/learning-k8s/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruffles.pw/posts/learning-k8s/</guid><description>Introduction Kubernetes is an open-source tool predominantly used by big tech companies to scale and manage their applications.
While I am not a big tech company (yet), I thought it best that I learn how to use it should the case arise that I may need it.
The Plan The general idea was to have some sort of simple service sat behind Kubernetes that demonstrates that the service is truly scaled and the load is balanced between nodes.</description></item><item><title>Should you get started with ASP.NET Core?</title><link>https://ruffles.pw/posts/aspnetcore-first-look/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ruffles.pw/posts/aspnetcore-first-look/</guid><description>NOTE: This post is ported from Illusive. You can find it here.
tl;dr: It&amp;rsquo;s pretty cool you should try it
Web development in C# (while I understand why some people hate it), is actually quite a painless process, everything seems to fit together nicely if you understand most of the concepts before starting a project.
In fact, I got this forum working relatively easily using just the docs and a little help from some experienced users of the framework.</description></item></channel></rss>